All Singing! All Dancing! All Flesh Eating!
Cannibal! The Musical is a comedy, western,
thriller film directed by Trey Parker.
Heading through Colorado Territory in search of gold and women, Alferd Packer and his group of bemused companions find themselves lost, starving and musically inspired by the
obstacles they confront along the way, including a die-hard Confederate cyclops, a trio of surly trappers, a tribe of Japanese-speaking "Indians," and ultimately, each other.
Alferd Packer, played by Trey Parker.
James Humphries, played by Matt Stone.
George Noon, played by Dian Bachar.
Shannon Bell, played by Ian Hardin.
Isreal Swan, played by Jon Hegel.
Indian Chief, played by Masao Maki.
The Musical (originally known as Alferd Packer: The Musical) is a 1993 American musical Western black comedy film directed, written, produced, co-scored by and starring Trey Parker in his
directorial debut while studying at the University of Colorado at Boulder, before reaching fame with South Park alongside his friend Matt Stone who also stars in and produced the film.
It is loosely based on the true story of Alfred "Alferd" Packer and the sordid details of the trip
from Utah to Colorado that left his five fellow travelers dead and partially eaten.
Trey Parker (credited as Juan Schwartz) stars as Alferd Packer, with frequent
collaborators Stone, Dian Bachar, and others playing the supporting roles.
A live staged version was performed at Sierra College,
in Rocklin, California, in May 1998.
It was followed by Dad's Garage Theater, Atlanta Georgia, in the fall of 1998.
The Dad's Garage version is highlighted in the special
features of Troma's DVD release of the movie.
The show has continued to find small theaters and audiences
across America and beyond for many years.
In 2001, a production was staged Off-Broadway at the
Kraine Theater on East 4th Street in New York.
In 2011, producer Jason McHugh released a book titled
Shpadoinkle: The Making of Cannibal!
The Musical which chronicles all aspects of the
creation and continuation of the Cannibal!
The Musical cult phenomenon.
Though not a success, the film would manage to attract the attention of Pam Brady, who was at the time an assistant to then-Fox executive Brian
Graden, with Parker and Stone's relationship with Brady and Graden ultimately becoming the key to the history of South Park.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.